Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Biology, Division of Systematic Biology, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Biology, Division of Systematic Biology, records
1949-1970
SC0256
Stanford Oceanographic Expedition
Stanford University. Department of Biology. Division of Systematic Biology.
3 Linear feet
Primarily office files regarding the Station such as information on the Te Vega program, the opening of the new Hopkins Marine Station facility, and graduates of the station. Also includes faculty meeting minutes, a study for apartment units at the Station, files from the Division of Systematic Biology, and unpublished reports from Te Vega expeditions, 1967-68.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers, Department of Biology, 1981, and Hopkins Marine Station Library, 1993.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Hopkins Marine Station, in Pacific Grove, California, was founded in 1893 by Stanford University as the Hopkins Seaside Laboratory. It is administered through the Division of Systematic Biology of Stanford's Department of Biology.
Description of the Collection
Primarily office files regarding the Station such as information on the Te Vega program, the opening of the new Hopkins Marine Station facility, and graduates of the station. Also includes faculty meeting minutes, a study for apartment units at the Station, files from the Division of Systematic Biology, and unpublished reports from Te Vega expeditions, 1967-68.
Access Terms
Brandin, Alf E.; Brooks, Howard E.; Creighton, Kenneth D.; Gilmartin, Malvern.; Grobstein, Clifford, 1916-; Holm, Richard W.; Hopkins Marine Station; Kennedy, Donald, 1931-; Miller, William F.; Morales, Hilbert.; Price, Donald L.; Ray, Dixie Lee.; Sears, Robert R. (Robert Richardson); Stanford University. Department of Biology. Division of Systematic Biology.; Stanford University. Department of Zoology. Faculty.; Sterling, J. E. Wallace, (John Ewart Wallace), 1906-1985; Thurber, James.; Marine biology.; Minutes.; Te Vega.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Hopkins Marine Station – Te Vega Program April, 1966- (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hopkins Marine Station – Te Vega Program March, 1957 – March 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hopkins Marine Station – Proteus Proposal to NSE, July 1, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Te Vega Expedition (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hopkins Marine Station Opening (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hopkins Marine Station – Gilmartin Biological Oceanography Program (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hopkins Marine Station – Te Vega Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hopkins Marine Station, Sept. 1, 1963 – March 31, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hopkins Marine Station, Jan. 1, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hopkins Marine Station, Sept. 1, 1966 – Dec. 31, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Graduates (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, Sept. 30, 1964 – Dec. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hopkins Marine Station, thru Aug. 31, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hopkins Marine Station Studies for Apartment Units (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ten year appraisal, May 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hopkins Marine Station various proposals – long range studies, 1965-1975; Master Plan, Mar. 29, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hopkins Marine Station – Peru (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, Oct. 1, 1958 – June 10, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hopkins Marine Station, Apr. 1, 1965 – Aug. 31, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, Oct. 14, 1949 – May 28, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Biology building correspondence, Dec. 31, 1963 – July 21, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Division of Systematic Biology Zoological Connections – California Academy of Sciences (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Division of Systematic Biology letters re future of Systematics, etc. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Division of Systematic Biology construction (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Division of Systematic Biology NHM (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Division of Systematic Biology Natural History Museum Zoological Collection (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Oceanographic Expedition 16. Gulf of California., Sept. 16 – Dec. 1, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Oceanographic Expedition 17. Eastern Tropical Pacific. Equatorial Current System and Galapagos Archipelago., Jan. 3 – Mar. 24, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Stanford Oceanographic Expedition 19. Eastern Tropical Pacific. Equatorial Current System and Galapago Archipelago., June 26 – Sept. 1, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Stanford Oceanographic Expedition 20. A Broad Inquiry into the Bilogical Oceanography of the Eastern Tropical Pacific., Sept. 16 – Dec. 1, 1968 (Box 4)
  - R.V. Te Vega Conversion Specifications, 1962-63. Companies involved are National Steel and Shipbuilding and Harco Engineering; includes 1 drawing. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Oceanographic Expedition 18. Eastern Tropical Pacific. Ecological, Systematic, and Distributional Studies of the Coastal Fauna and Flora between Paita, Peru and Magdalena Bay, Baja California., April 4-June 16, 1968 (Box 6)